So, far we've built a quantity picker.
これまで、量ピッカーを作りました。
&gt;&gt; Right. And
&gt;&gt; そうだね、そして
the next place to go in the app is the price.
次の課題は金額だね。
&gt;&gt; Yes.
&gt;&gt; その通り。
The price is right.
金額ですね。
So, price is an integer so far, but we want to move beyond that and
今のところ金額は整数ですが、 それより先に行ってみようと思います。
use strings.
文字列を使います。
&gt;&gt; You mean, this type of string?
&gt;&gt; こういう列のこと？
&gt;&gt; No I mean like this type of string.
&gt;&gt;　そうじゃなくて、こういう列のこと。
&gt;&gt; Huh.
&gt;&gt; へぇ。
&gt;&gt; So a string is just a sequence of characters.
&gt;&gt; 文字列はその名の通り字の列です。
&gt;&gt; So wait. How does this work with the price then?
&gt;&gt; それが金額とどんな関係があるの？
&gt;&gt; So we're going to change the screen so that it says total.
&gt;&gt; これを使って「合計」と書いて、
And then $15.
そして１５ドルって書くの。
So it's not just a number, now it has some text with it as well.
数字だけじゃなくて、テキストも加わってくるの。
&gt;&gt; Numbers and text.
&gt;&gt; 数字とテキストだね。
&gt;&gt; Yeah. Isn't that awesome?
&gt;&gt; そう、すごいでしょ。
This is from the party that you may or may not have [LAUGH] been invited to.
これ、あなたが呼ばれなかったパーティーに あったものじゃない？
Over the next few videos we'll talk about using strings
次のいくつかのビデオでは、Javaアプリでの
in our Just Java app.
文字列の使い方について学びます。
Specifically, we'll learn how to create and update string variables in the app.
具体的には、文字列の作成、 そして更新の方法です。
Then we'll change the app so that under the price header it says total, $15 or
そしてアプリを書き換えて、「total $15」というように、
whatever the price is based on the quantity ordered.
を量に応じた金額を表示したいと思います。
We'll also show the text,
お客さんが来るように、
Thank you, because we're excited about having any customers at all.
「Thank you」というテキストもいれます。
You might be wondering why don't we just put all of this text
このテキストを全てXMLファイルに 記入すればいい
inside the XML layout?
と思う方もいると思います。
Well, we could, but the problem is that the quantity can change and
それは可能ですが、量は変化するので、
when we hit the order button, we want the price to be updated here.
それに応じて金額を更新しなければいけません。
So this text needs to accurately reflect the price based on the quantity.
なのでこのテキストは量に依存します。
By using a string variable, we can change the value of the text while
文字列変数を使えば、 アプリ上で、
the app is running without having to hard code it into the whole XML layout.
XMLレイアウトに直接記入しなくても その値を変えることができます。
Here's an example from real apps that you may recognize.
皆さんにもおなじみのアプリの例です。
When you receive an incoming call you see the person's name at the top
電話を受信すると、上に相手の名前が
of the screen.
表示されます。
We can't put this name directly into the XML layout
相手によって名前が変わるので、
because it will change depending on who calls you, unless all your family and
XMLレイアウトに直接記入することはできません。
The best thing to do is to store this name in a string variable.
最善の方法は、この名前を文字列として 記憶させることです。
That way you can update it depending on who calls you.
そうすれば、相手によって表示を変えることができます。
Then when we show this screen we can just display the latest name
このスクリーンを表示するときに、 その文字列の値を
that is stored in that variable.
表示すればいいだけです。
In the News and Weather app, we see a list of the top news stories.
ニュースや天気予報アプリでは、 トップニュースおリストがあります。
When we build the XML layout, we can't just specifically hard code
XMLレイアウトを作るときに、特定のニュースを
these specific news stories into the XML layout.
直接記入することはできません。
As much as I love reading about the Winter Olympics,
冬季オリンピックもいいですが、
I do want to see other news articles as well.
他のニュースもみたいですよね。
So we can store the information for each news story,
なので、記事の題名など、それぞれのニュースの
like the article title, as a string variable, because that can change.
情報をを文字列変数そして記憶させれば、 更新することができます。
For the next task I'm going to provide you with some code and
次のエクササイズでは、皆さんにあるコードを渡します。
I'm going to have you make those changes in your app.
そして、以上の更新を記入してもらいます。
Then you'll run the app and then observe what happens.
それを実行して、結果を見てみます。
I'll ask you some questions to see if you can try to figure out
何が起こっているのかを理解するために、
what's going on.
いくつか質問をします。
The first change is to modify the submitOrder method.
ますはsubmitOrderメソッドを変更することです。
You can remove the code that's already in between the opening and
中かっこの中にあるものを消去して、
closing braces and then replace it with these two lines of code.
そしてこの二行のコードを記入してください。
Adding this code will give you an error, so I want you to also
このコードを記入するとエラーが発生します。
add the displayMessage method, which we've provided in the instructor notes.
なので、この指導書にある displayMessageメソッドも加えてください。
In the instructor notes, you'll find this Gist of code.
指導書には、このGistのコードが載っています。
Go ahead and select the whole thing,
全てを選択してください。
from the comment all the way to the last closing brace.
コメントから最後の終結かっこまでです。
You can treat this method like a black box,
このメソッドをブラックボックスとして考えてもらって 結構です。
you don't have to worry about what's going on Inside of the method, you just
内容は気にしなくていいので、
need to know that you want to add it to the MainActivity so that you can use it.
MainActivityに加えて使えれば大丈夫です。
Back in Android Studio,
Android Studioに戻って、
in the MainActivity.java file, I'm going to paste in this new method.
MainActivity.javaファイルに、この新しいメソッドを ペイストします。
I can paste it anywhere in the MainActivity, but
MainActivityのどこにでもペイストでできますが、
I'm just going to put it right after the displayPrice method.
displayPriceメソッドの後にペイストしておきます。
And I'm going to put it after
このdisplayPriceメソッドの終結かっこの
the closing brace of the displayPrice method.
後にペイストします。
Notice that it's also inside of the closing brace of the MainActivity.
MainActivityのかっこの中にあることに 注意してください
The MainActivity has an opening brace right here,
MainActivityには始まりのかっこがここにあり、
and everything inside of it is contained within the MainActivity.
ここから全てがMainActivityの中に入っています。
And then you have a closing brace for the MainActivity here.
そしてここにMainActivityの終結かっこがあります。
Once we've added the displayMessage method in,
displayMessageメソッドを加えたら、
we can now modify the submitOrder method.
submitOrderメソッドを変えることができます。
I'm going to erase the code that we already have inside
submitOrderメソッドにすでにある
the submitOrder method.
コードを消去して、
Then according to the quiz image, I'm going to add the new code here.
問題にあったように、新しいコードを 記入します。
Intentionally I'm not giving you too many details on what I just did.
ここで何をしたかはあえて見せません。
I want you to try it out in your version of the app, run it, and
皆さんには、自身で加えてもらって、 実行して、
see what happens.
何が起きるかを見てもらいます。
After that I want you to answer these questions.
その後に次の質問に答えてください。
What happens when you click on the order button in the app now?
アプリのORDERボタンをクリックすると何が起きるか。
If you take a look at the submit order code more closely,
このsubmitOrderコードをよく見てみると、
we actually created a string variable.
文字列変数が作られていることが分かります。
Even though we haven't gone over the code for string variables, I want you to
文字列のコードをまだ学んでいませんが、
make your best guess as to, what do you think the variable name is?
変数の名前が何か、
And what do you think the variable value is?
そして変数の値は何かを考えてもらいます。
When you are done go ahead and continue.
それが終わったら、次へ進んでください。